Curriculum Vitae

Personal Details

Name: Tusabe Lawrence

Nationality: Ugandan

Date of Birth: 19th November, 1989

Marital status Single Gender Male

Address Kuukha Systems Ltd

P.O Box 37572 Kampala (U)

Plot 933 Kireka – Namugongo Rd, Nelvin House

(+256) 781 587497 or (+256) 703 587497

Itusabe@gmail.com

Summary

Good level of expertise in information systems, software development, data management & security and web intelligence.

High level of expertise in web technologies including but not limited to: Joomla, Wordpress, PHP, HTML, database, java, and MYSQL.

Over 3 years of progressive professional expertise in information and communication technology development and Teaching.

Have a strong background in the following IT area: software & web development, ICT Teaching, Enterprise architecture, Infrastructure management, Project planning & management, Leadership & team management, e-government & resource planning and many more.

Objective

To attain a full position in the field of computing where I can demonstrate my technical, business and computing skills and contribute to the organization development.

Personal Profile

Results-driven, logical and methodical approach to achieving tasks and objectives, uses initiative to develop effective solutions to problems, strives for quality and applies process and discipline towards optimizing performance. Am extremely reliable, adaptable, and flexible and seeks new responsibilities irrespective of reward and recognition and technically competent in ICT software development, teaching, administration and seeks and finds good outcomes to challenges. I possess the right skills, experience, behavior, attitude, and morality.

EDUCATION

1.	Makerere University CoCIS Currently on Masters in computer science (Major Security)	9/2014 to date
2.	2. BSc Honours (CS) – Westville Campus, UKN	10/2012 – 9/2013
3.	Makerere University CoCIS Bachelor of Science in computer science (Second upper)	9/2009 – 5/2012
4.	Makerere ICT Solution Certificate in I.T Essentials PC Hardware and software	2011
5.	Hilton High School Mukono Uganda Advanced Certificate of Education (UACE)	2007 - 2008
6.	Hilton High School Mukono Uganda Certificate of Education (UCE)	2003 - 2006
7.	Nagojje Binikira Primary School Primary Leaving Examination (PLE)	1995 – 2002

TEACHING EXPERENCE

The following are some of the courses that I have been teaching:

- Computer Literacy
- Fundamentals of Web design
- Programming Methodology (java, C, Python)
- Algorithm Analysis and Design (Data Structures and Algorithm)
- Artificial Intelligence
- Hardware Repair and Maintenance (A++)
- Operating Systems
- Systems Administration
- Database Management Systems

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Uganda Christian University (UCU) Mukono

6/2012 to date

Tutor for Computer practical & Web developer, Faulty of science: Some of the course units taught: Programming Methodology (using Java and C), Website Design & Hosting (PHP, CSS, JavaScript, and HTML), and Faculty website development & Maintenance.

LIJIF International American College of Health Sciences (Ntinda)

10/2013- 5/2014

Instructor of Computer programs: Some of the course units taught: Programming Methodology (using Java and C), Database Management System, Operating Systems, Data Communication & Networks,

Fundamentals of Web design (PHP, CSS, JavaScript, and HTML), Skills development (Visual basic) and Computer Literacy.

WORK EXPERIENCE

A. Kuukha Systems Limited

10/2013 to date

Software Developer/Programmer - The following projects were accomplished.

1) NHCC Intranet site

Developer of intranet site software in share point 2013 for National Housing Co-operation Company Ltd, for sharing of file among the company employees to elimination manual system. December 2013 to January 2015. I played the role of a developer subcontracted by NCR Company, project team leader Biliba

2) Maintenance Management System

Developer of MMS: Software that keeps track of records for machine breakdowns, machine services, spare part usage & requisition in store and technician work for ease accessibility by the management. It's installed at Luuka Plastics Limited Uganda at the factory in Kawempe on intranet. I played the role of programmer under the leadership of Engineer Edward Matumbwe and Mr. Paul Bakaki, programming languages used; PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, October 2013 to December 2013. It was installed successfully and it's working as expected.

3) SCIU Inventory system

Developer of SCIU Inventory system, the system handles products in stock for sell along with their purchase orders, invoice requests, delivery notes, gate pass note, invoices and goods received note. It's installed at Service and Computer Industry Uganda (SCIU). Programming languages used: PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, May 2013 to December 2013. It was installed on intranet.

4) Desktop Applications

I have successfully designed two (2) desktop applications which include; Inference system for heart diagnosis, in my final year research project for the Bachelor's degree and Becks clinic patient management system for Becks clinic in Bwaise, under the supervision of Mr. Paul Bakaki

5) Websites Projects

I have planned, created, launched, and managed corporate web sites for high-profile Web Company clients and these include:

- Expertcage http://expertcage.com [3/2015]
- ➤ Platform for Social Justice Uganda http://justiceuganda.org [3/2015]
- Serenity Centre Organization http://serenitycentre.org [1/2015]
- > Afri-Sol http://afri-sol.org/ [10/2014]
- ➤ UCU Faculty of Science and Technology website http://tech.ucu.ac.ug [6/2014]
- Access freight services http://www.access.co.ug [4/2014]
- Uganda builder's directory, www.ugbuilder.com [3/2014]
- ➤ National Health Insurance Fund for Tanzania http://www.nhif.or.tz/ [10/2013]
- Connex travel services Ltd http://www.connextraveluganda.com [8/2013]
- Kampala Hash House Harriers http://www.kh3ug.org [4/2013]

B. World ICT Solutions

5/2012 - 9/2012

Team Leader: Being a team leader for World ICT Solutions, I have been involved in the following areas of specialization: ICT outsourcing, Website/Software design, development, maintenance & sales and company management.

C. Connex Travel Services

12/2011 - 5/2012

ICT Assistant: As an assistant, I was involved the following areas of ICT: Network setup and connectivity, computer hardware & software troubleshooting and website development and maintenance.

D. Makerere ICT Solution (MICTS)

1/2011- 11/2011

System Support Assistant: In charge of company systems, Recommended and maintained company systems. Instructor of ICT to staff and students, set-up and install hardware and software at user stations, Assembled, configured, installed, tested and repaired computer hardware and software.

RESEARCH INTERESTS:

- a) Expert systems: application of expert systems in medical and business area to minimize human errors
- b) Web technologies: application of new web technologies, development and maintenance of webbased system.
- c) Data and computer security: confidentiality, availability, authenticity and integrity requirements for different kinds of data both in the technical as well as in the legal sense.

Functional skills and areas of interest

a) Good level of expertise in information systems, IT Teaching, software development, data management & security, web intelligence systems and leadership & team management

Technical Expertise

- a) Languages: Java, PHP, Visual basic, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, XML, C/C++ and C#.
- b) **Applications:** MS SharePoint, MS Visual Studio, Eclipse, Netbeans, Dreamweaver, SPSS, Photo shop, illustrator, fireworks, MS Access, MS Word, MS Excel, MS Outlook and among others
- c) Database Systems: SQL Server, MySQL, MS Access
- d) Operating Systems: MS Vista, MS XP, MS Windows and Linux
- e) **Hardware:** Experienced with installation of mother boards, Operating system, internal or external modems, NICs, SCSI and IDE hard disks, SCSI floppy drives, SCSI I/O ports, and various printer configurations.

REFEREES

Mr. Paul Bakaki

Lecturer International University of East Africa

Faculty of Science and Technology

Tel: +256 71222779 / +256 702008850

Email: pbakaki@gmail.com

Mr. John Habere

Lecturer and Quality Assurance Coordinator Uganda Christian University Department of Computing and Technology

P.O Box 4, Mukono, Uganda

Tel: +256 793 836833 / +256 706 408988

Email: bwawire@technology.ucu.ac.ug, habere@kuukha.com

Engineer Edward Matumwe Manager NCR

P.O Box 2109, Kampala, Uganda

Tel: +256 712 751541 / +256 704 751541

Email: matumbwe@gmail.com